BENJAMÍN SAÚL ESCOBAR GARCÍA

Front-end Web Development



Front-end Developer with strong experience in HTML5, CSS3, and SCSS preprocessor; High expertise with Javascript and Angular 2+ Framework with PWA's. Experience with morphological image processing; development of transactional, medical, and geographic information systems; using Git tools and REST API's; and teamwork with Agile methodologies on interdisciplinary teams. Active self-taught learner. New technologies enthusiast, loving hardware world and passionate musician.

M <u>benjamin.s1.e@gmail.com</u>		bit.ly/DeProgramacionYT
in linkedin.com/in/benjaseg/? locale=en_US	<u>↓</u>	<u>benjalorc.github.io</u>

Experiences

Front-end Developer. AsteratNet.

Jul 2020-Dec 2020.

I created scalable functional components with **React.js 16**, powered by Server Side Rendering framework **Next.js**, and integrating **Material-UI** components in developed views. I built a **Backend for Frontend** to manage all **REST API** request prior to **JWT** authentication, and handled application state trough **Redux**. I managed tasks progress trough **Jira** and maintained a git repository on **GitHub** creating branches for every task, defined during **Scrum** meetings.

Front-end Developer. Oralsys.

Apr 2018-Apr 2020.

I developed components on **Angular 5-8**, powered by **Angular Material** components and CSS framework **Bootstrap 3**, handling data through a **REST API**, managing application state through **NgRx**, maintaining a git repository on **GitLab**, and managing progress through **Taiga** and **Asana**. I created scalable views for calendar management powered by **Fullcalendar** library. I adapted pdf documents creation using **PdfMake** library. I managed to handle RX image visualization and 3D Rendering using **Web Workers** and **Ami.js** library. I proposed my own problems solutions ideas and led freelancers hired for specific requirements. I debugged my own and third party front-end errors.

Front-end Developer. Seismology Center in Eastern University (CSUDO).

Sep 2017-Mar 2018.

I developed **Angular 4** components for capturing and fetching earthquakes geographic data, powered by CSS Framework **Bootstrap 4**, handling data through a **REST API**, maintaining a git repository on **GitHub**, and reporting my progress through **Trello**. I created an interactive web map for data geo-referencing, with custom icons and dynamic data visualization, powered by **Leaflet** library. I was able to lead problem-solving and managed to include extra features for calculating distances and areas measurements. I debugged front-end bugs due to system changes.

Full-Stack Developer(MEAN). UPTOS (Polytechnic University).

Oct 2016-Sep 2017.

I created a geographic information system to support decision-making using **Angular 4** and **Bootstrap 3** frameworks in front, **Node.js** with **Express** on the web server, and **Mongodb** as database management system. I designed **UML** artifacts for whole system design and documentation; handled user authentication through **JWT**; developed components for capturing population and students data from my own **REST API**, powered by **Mongoose** middleware for database connection; managed to include geo-referencing capabilities for data using **Leaflet** library; and maintained a git repository on **GitHub** for versioning. *Ad honorem* project as partial requirement in Computer Science career.

Courses

06/2020	CSS: Advanced Layouts with Grid	Linkedin Learning	3h 21m
06/2020	Learning React.js	Linkedin Learning	1h 0m
06/2020	PMI Agile Certified Practitioner	Linkedin Learning	1h 53m
06/2020	Scrum: The Basics	Linkedin Learning	1h 2m
05/2020	Learning 3D Graphics on the Web with Three.js	Linkedin Learning	2h 51m

Education

2016-Present	Bachelor of Science: Computer Science*	UPTOS (Polytechnic University)
2013-2016	Associate's in Computer Science	UPTOS (Polytechnic University)
2007-2013	High School in Computer Science	Nuestra Señora del Valle (High School)

^{*}Unfinished (final year / formalities)

Knowledge / Skills / Proficiency

- ☑ **Programming:** High expertise in **Javascript** and frameworks or libraries based on this language, with **PWA** development experience on **Angular 2**+.
- ☑ Web Layouts: Strong experience with HTML5 and CSS3 trends with Responsive Design, mastering CSS Grid, SCSS preprocessor usage, and handling Bootstrap 3 4 framework, effectively enhancing usability and improving UI/UX.
- ☑ **Versioning:** Git Version control management on main platforms as GitHub, Bitbucket or GitLab.
- ☑ **C1 English:** High conversational, reading and writing **english** level, both for technical and commercial english.
- ☑ Adaptability to environment changes. Quick self-taught learning in development time.
- ☑ Proactivity, problems analysis and solving capabilities.
- ☑ Teamwork skills. **Agile** practitioner. Mind-open to accept and offer support.